MOHANRAJ P (ELECTRICAL ENGINEER)

Bangalore - 560003,KA, India. +919940944380 | mohanrajpalanisamy2412@gmail.com

Objective

A Dedicated and driven professional with 8+years of experience in Electrical and Electronics Engineering. Specialized in Electrical Design and Implement in Robotics and Automation systems, Aerospace sector, and manufacturing industry. To Apply my Analytical and Technical skills to complete the Task on time.

Experience

• Opal Metal Engineering Ltd, Bangalore

02 May 2024 - Present

Electrical Engineer

Develop and Implemented Electrical engineering strategies, plans and designs for Robotics and Automation Tablet strips cutting machine in R&D Team.

Created Electrical system drawings, wiring diagrams and schematics and Bill of Materials.

Performed Troubleshooting of complex Electrical systems to identify root cause of issues.

Electrical control panel and cable sizing and constraint the components. Analyzed test results to diagnose malfunctions in Electrical systems.

Designed automated control systems using computer aided software tools FESTO Plcs, Advantech i/o cards. Collaborated with other engineers on design projects to ensure quality and safety standards.

Shobikaa Impex Pvt Ltd, Karur, India

MAR 2022 - APR 2024

Electrical Shift Engineer

Company Overview: Largest mosquito nets(LLIN) manufacturing industry.

Regular Analyzing of organization Electrical load and demand analysis.

Operation and maintenance of substation equipments like VCBs, ACBs, Switchgears, 1600,2500kva rating transformers, 750,1500kva DGs.

Extruder machines, blower motors, knitting machines, stenter machines, cooling towers, compressors, lighting systems and EoT cranes.

General maintenance and breakdown troubleshooting.

Power failure solving skills and bus coupling methods, 300 kva UPS systems operation and maintenance work. Knowledge of Heaters, RTDs, Thermocouples, SSRs, VFDs Mitsubishi and Siemens.

Air Conditioner servicing like voltas, bluestar, daikin.

• Floflex Industries LLP

JAN 2020 - MAR 2022

Electrical Engineer

Company Overview: MS and HDPE Pipe manufacturing plant.

Preventive and breakdown maintenance of HT/LT panels, switchgears, lighting systems, Timers, Hydraulic and pneumatic solenoid valves, furnace ovens.

Experience in welding machines like arc, plasma cutting machines.

EoT crane 30ton capacity operation and fault attending. Periodic maintenance of compressor s, chillers, Vaccum blowers, cooling towers and RO systems.

• HAL- Aerospace Division amc of Sankeerth associates

APR 2016 - SEP 2019

Electrical Site Engineer

General Electrical maintenance and operation in 11kv substation RMU systems, and Transformer periodical oil test and oil filtrations.

Highbay, Lowbay lightings, UPS systems, scanners, fire alarms.

Maintain various records, such as monthly operating reviews, Daily work logsheets, and materials records. Good understanding of Electrical drawing, planning of projects, Errection and maintenance. Safety process oriented technical skills.

Supervised a team of electricians during the commissioning process of new installations.

VSB Engineering College - Anna University Chennai B. E- Electrical and Electronics Engineering 6.74 Rangasamy Gounder Hr.Sec.School Nadayanur HSC 64.4 Rangasamy Gounder Hr.Sec.School Nadayanur SSLC 71.6

Skills

Education

- Electrical cotrol panel design and components selection
- AutoCAD Electrical 2D drawings and autoCAD Inventor design
- Operation and Troubleshooting machines, Root cause Analysis
- Knowledge in Servodrives, Servomotors, VFDs, pumps and ind. motors controlling systems.
- FMEAs, 5s systems, bill of materials, inventory checklists.
- Knowledge in NEC, IE Codes, IMS standards.
- Design risk analysis and testing of Electrification components and systems.

Projects

SBCM and Dispensing control panel in Automation

To design and drawn the Electrical control panel, in both sbcm and dispensing team as well components selection, cable sizing and wire harness.

To complete my task is fulfilled with in a time.

Electro mechanical system

To complete the Electromechanical system in pneumatic solenoid controller and sensor position arrangement.

300kva and Batter setup

In 300kva ups system batteries 200ah 60nos are changed and connection both input/output side under my supervision.

• DG system Alternator

750kva DG Stanford alternator coil was shorted, so remove from inside safely and again Refixed the alternator with follow the proper safety standards.

· Transformer oil filteration

2000kva, 2500kva, 1000kva transformer oil filteration are did under my team supervision.

Electrical safety

MARRIED

Knowledge in Electrical safety systems Do's and Dont's. Knowledge in Electrical fire Extinguisher types. Grounding systems.

Additional Information

Electrical C License No:C59575 Passport No: T9357622 DOB:11.04.1994

Known Language: English, Tamil, Kannada, Telugu